airnewzealand.com 2015-12-06

# Air New Zealand Privacy Policy - Legal - Information - Air New Zealand

### 1.1 Cookies and online tracking technologies

We use cookies and similar technology on our websites to allow us to improve site performance and enhance your online experience. 

Please read our Cookie Policy to learn about the cookies and other online tracking technologies used on Air New Zealand websites, mobile applications and mobile websites to collect personal information about you from your computer, mobile or other device.

If you visit an Air New Zealand website, mobile application or mobile website, we and third parties may use cookies and other online tracking technologies to collect personal information about you from your computer, mobile or device. This information may include:

  * your domain name and your IP address;
  * your online Air New Zealand Account password information;
  * your internet browser software and type of computer or mobile device used;
  * your operating system and platform;
  * your device geo-locator information (if you have downloaded our mobile application) so we can provide you with flight arrival and travel information;
  * your preferred webpage layout and language preferences;
  * the path you took to get to our websites;
  * information about your online activity on our websites, such as web pages viewed, paths you used through our websites, options you selected and the search terms you used;
  * the bookings you made on our websites and the bookings you abandoned, including the information you entered when you made or started to make a booking; and
  * if you visit the online Airpoints Mall, information about your online activity, browsing preferences and online retailer purchases.

### 1.2 Booking information 

We collect and use the personal information that you provide to Air New Zealand and to ‘Reservations Agents’ and the information that Reservation Agents provide to us in relation to your bookings for flights and travel related services (for example, if you make a booking or if a booking is made on your behalf). The term ‘Reservations Agents’ includes reservations agents of Air New Zealand and Air New Zealand Holidays, third party travel agents, third party online travel agents, airline customer service representatives and Airpoints representatives.

The personal information we may collect about you in relation to a booking includes your name, address, date of birth, nationality, passport number, credit card details, bank account details, phone numbers, email address, flight and other travel details, your special meal or special assistance requests, loyalty programme membership, the identity of persons who may be travelling with you on your booking, their personal details, if provided, and any other personal information you may volunteer (or which may be volunteered on your behalf) as part of the booking.

### 1.3 Information we receive from other sources

If you make a booking with us, use any of our services or use our websites, we may receive information about you from third parties. We work closely with third parties (including for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

If you are an Airpoints Member or if you hold any account associated with us, you acknowledge and agree that we may collect personal social media information about you, either from you directly or from third parties (if the information is publically or commercially available). Such personal social media information will supplement our customer databases and will be processed by us for marketing and business development purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### 1.4 Sensitive information

We may request and collect (from you or a Reservations Agent) your ‘sensitive information’, such as information about your religious beliefs or health / dietary requirements, for the purpose of helping to fulfil your special needs requests (for example if you have requested a special meal for health or religious reasons). We may disclose ‘sensitive information’ about you to our agents and third parties (such as airports, catering companies and their business partners) for the purpose of fulfilling your special needs requests. These agents and third parties may be located outside of New Zealand or the European Economic Area in countries who may not have data protection laws that are comparable to the laws of the country in which you reside.

Whenever you provide us with sensitive information (including information about your physical and/or mental health, race, religious and other similar beliefs and criminal records), you consent to Air New Zealand processing your sensitive information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### 1.5 Medical and other occasions

We may collect and disclose personal information about Air New Zealand passengers, including sensitive details about your physical and/or mental health, race, religious and other similar beliefs and criminal records, to third party medical, safety and/or security personnel if we believe that the collection or disclosure of the information is desirable to lessen or prevent a serious threat to an individual’s life, health or safety or a serious threat to public health or public safety; or if we believe that it would be in the interests of aviation safety and security.

We may collect (either directly or from third party airline carriers) personal information about passengers who exhibit disruptive behaviour onboard any aircraft. This may include the passenger’s name, flight booking details, and information about the nature of the disruptive behaviour. We may disclose this information to security personnel, law enforcement agencies and to third party airline carriers if we consider that disclosure is reasonably appropriate in the interests of aviation safety and security.

### 1.6 Koru Members

If you are a Koru Member, we collect the personal information you provide us as part of your Koru membership and information about your use of Koru membership benefits, in addition to any personal information collected as part of your Airpoints membership (see section 1.7 below). This personal information may be processed for the purposes described in section 2 below.

### 1.7 Airpoints Members

If you are an Airpoints Member, we collect personal information about your Airpoints membership. This includes the information you provide on your Airpoints application form; your Airpoints number, your online Air New Zealand Account password information; your travel history; country of residence; information about any giftees you may register on your Gifting Register; and if you choose to complete an optional ‘Travel Profile’ on our website, we will collect this information.

Information from social media may be collected about Airpoint Members, from third parties, in accordance with section 1.3 of this Privacy Policy.

We also collect personal information about you from our Airpoints Partners including information about your transaction and purchase history at retail stores and online stores, where you use your Airpoints membership, and/or where you earn Airpoint Dollars and Status Points.

We may collect personal information about you from third parties to verify your identity and address.

We may collect personal information about you from our third party business partners to assist in identifying suitable offers and promotions from us and our third party business partners that you might be interested in. We may also collect personal information about you that is publically available.

If you are an Air New Zealand Airpoints credit card holder, OneSmart or Travelcard holder, we may collect personal information about you from our third party business partners about your membership and use of these products, including transaction history information.

If you apply for or hold an Air New Zealand Airpoints credit card, we may collect personal information from Kiwibank and MasterCard in relation to your application for and the use of your Air New Zealand Airpoints credit card, including your transaction history information.

If you apply for or hold an OneSmart Account, we may collect personal information about you from BNZ and MasterCard in relation to the use of your OneSmart Account, including your transaction history information.

If you are an Airpoints Member, we may also collect, use and disclose personal information about you in accordance with the Airpoints Terms and Conditions.

### 1.8 Promotions and surveys

If you enter an Air New Zealand competition or promotion, we will collect the information you provide as part of your entry. If you provide us with the names and contact details of any other people that you would like to have participate in our contests or promotions, we will also collect this information, and we draw your attention to section 6 below.

If you complete a survey conducted by or on behalf of Air New Zealand, including an ‘airnzmyvoice’ survey, we will collect information about you in your survey answers, including your name, unless you choose to answer anonymously.

### 1.9 Inflight entertainment and purchases

If you travel on an Air New Zealand flight, we may collect information about your use of the onboard inflight entertainment system. This may include information about: your inflight purchases; your inflight entertainment setting preferences; your audio and audio-visual preferences and playlists; and your survey answers, if you choose to complete a survey using the inflight entertainment system.
